drugfree.org 2007-09-15

# Privacy Policy - The Partnership For a Drugfree America

| 

### Partnership for a Drug-Free America  
Privacy Policy

#### Privacy Assurance

_We will not willfully disclose any individually identifiable information about you to any outside source without your express consent._

The Partnership for a Drug-Free America (the Partnership) is committed to protecting the personal information you choose to share with us. Below you will find our privacy assurance and some additional information about how we gather information about our registered users, why we gather it, and what we do with it. Please see Terms and Conditions of Use for more information about the use of the Partnership site. 

#### How does the Partnership use cookies?

The Partnership uses cookies to facilitate the login process for you to access sections that require registration to post or contribute to the site. When you register in these sections, we assign a unique user id to you and we place a cookie on your computer, which will remind our system of that USER ID the next time you visit the site. This cookie allows you to access the areas of the site that require registration without having to log on multiple times. If you choose to log out, the cookie we set in registration will be deleted and we will then set another cookie like it on your computer next time you log in. 

Please note: Nothing in a cookie allows anyone to identify you individually. Your computer is assigned a number and that number is tracked using the cookie. This number is only meaningful in the context of our secure database system and your personalized version of the Partnership site. 

#### What information do we gather?

The only individually identifiable information that we collect about you is that which you provide to us through registration and submission forms, polls and surveys that you choose to fill out. This information will be closely protected and used for internal purposes only. We will never willfully release your personal information to any third party other than vendors who provide us with web and other technology services (see more about third party vendors under “Registrant Donor Database” below.) 

We also collect information about aggregate site usage. Statistics that we gather about unique visits, repeat visits and page views are all based on IP address, not on your individual activities. 

#### Site Registration: “My Partnership”

When you register as a "member" of the nationwide Partnership for a Drug-Free America web site, [www.drugfree.org](http://www.drugfree.org/), you will be required to provide the following information: your email address, login name, password, and zip code. In addition, you have the option of letting the Partnership contact you in the future. This form also requests additional (optional) information, including your name and address, demographic status and areas of interest. This information helps us define the demographic make-up or our online visitors, improve the site organization, edit existing features, and develop new features to meet visitors’ needs. 

#### Donating to the Partnership: 

When you donate to the Partnership online you submit confidential credit card information, contact information, and acknowledge whether you would like to be contacted by the Partnership via email in the future. We recognize the importance of respecting the integrity of this material and limit access only to personnel authorized to process your request. 

You may also choose to make a donation in memory of someone or in honor/tribute of someone in recovery. When you make a donation of this type, the amount of your gift is shown only on your receipt. The person or family you designate will receive an acknowledgment ecard or regular-mail card in your name if you choose to send one. We collect this additional contact information in order to honor your request to send an acknowledgement. The information is not used for any direct mail or email databases or solicitations, nor is it shared with any third parties. Email-communications from the Partnership are only issued through the direct consent of each unique visitor (known as “opting in”). 

Online donors are also offered the option of choosing to let the Partnership contact them via email in the future. 

#### Registrant (“MyPartnership”) and Donor Database 

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

Registration and donor data is maintained in a highly secure environment by our vendor, Kintera, Inc. Kintera provides technology services to many non-profit organizations and is considered a market leader in this sector. The Partnership uses Kintera’s services to maintain our registrant (member) donor and email newsletter database. We use Kintera because of their commitment to the highest levels of security and confidentiality in dealing with our registrant and donor data. The web servers, databases and associated equipment are in guarded and secured commercial co-location facilities. Kintera does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

#### Choice/Opt-Out, Correcting/Updating Information

If you would like to request access to review, update, change or delete your “MyPartnership” profile information you have supplied, you may do so by logging into “MyPartnership” at [www.drugfree.org](http://www.drugfree.org/) or by sending an email to [webmaster@drugfree.org](mailto:webmaster@drugfree.org). 

Additional options for contacting the Partnership include 

You can send mail to the following postal address:   
Partnership for a Drug-Free America  
Suite 1601  
405 Lexington Avenue  
New York, NY 10174   
You can also call the following telephone number: (212) 922-1560. 

#### Stories: Personal Stories, Recovery Stories and Memorial Stories

Many visitors to our site have stories to share about their experiences, or experiences of their friends and siblings, with substance abuse, recovery, treatment, prevention, etc. We created the “Stories” and “Personal Stories” sections to enable visitors to submit a personal story for possible posting to our site. Only select stories will be posted to the site. Submitting gender, age range, ethnic background, city and state is optional. When you submit a story to this section, an email address is required in case we need to contact you. By submitting a story, you automatically give us permission to post the story on our web site. The Partnership reserves the right to edit the story for publication. Your email address will not be published, and your email address will not be shared with any outside organizations or individuals. Please review our Terms and Conditions of Use for more information. 

We created a Memorials site for individuals to submit memorials in memory of loved ones lost to drugs or alcohol. For Memorial stories that we publish, we may follow-up to with the submitter to verify the story details. Memorials published on the site contain the real first name and last name of the deceased. We also ask for the year of the deceased's birth and death as well as the substance they used or died from. For longer-formatted stories we develop in house, specific dates of birth and death of the deceased may be used. 

#### Online "Volunteerism" Submissions: 

The online registration form includes optional “areas of interest” and may include a check box for volunteering. The information that you provide here is forwarded to the local Partnership Chapter/Alliance in your area, who will then contact you about volunteerism opportunities best suited to your interests. 

#### Registration Termination

The Partnership reserves the right to terminate your account if it learns that you have provided false or misleading registration information. 

#### eNewsletter Sign-up

Our eNewsletter sign-up section requires you to enter your email address to sign up for email newsletters. When you choose to sign up for one of our email newsletters, your email address is used solely to provide the newsletter to which you subscribe. Your email address won't be shared with any outside organizations or individuals without your express permission. Whenever you do receive a mailing from us you will always find an easy method to unsubscribe within the contents of the email. 

#### Online Surveys

Our occasional online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like email or mailing address). We use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about the Partnership and its activities. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings (see the Choice/Opt-out section below). Other data collected by online surveys is used to educate the Partnership about the interests and concerns of its supporters and general site visitors concerning the Partnership's mission, programs and events. This information is not shared with other organizations. The Partnership operates email discussion, and contact lists to reach its members who request such information. Such services are run both by the Partnership and contracted vendors. These email addresses whether housed on the Partnership servers or those of our third-party contractor are never shared with any other organization and users may opt out of participating or receiving email information from the Partnership at any time. Instructions are contained within each email sent. 

#### “Tell-A-Friend,” “Email Others”, "Tell Others"

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, programs or events, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. The Partnership will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site to learn about the feature, program or event. The Partnership stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. The friend may contact the Partnership at [webmaster@drugfree.org](mailto:webmaster@drugfree.org) to request the removal of this information from the database. 

#### Security 

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. This includes a firewall and 24 monitoring of site activities by our hosting service provider as well as 128-bit SSL encryption (where allowable by law) on all transaction oriented operations between you and the Partnership via our transaction service provider. While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to your information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers' information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store identifiable personal information on are kept in a secure environment, behind a locked cage. 

#### Contact Information 

If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our privacy policies or practices, we would like to know what they are so we can address them. Please contact us at (212) 315-8799 or email us. 

#### Changes to Privacy Policy

The Partnership may at any time revise this Privacy Policy by updating this posting. You are bound by any such revisions and should therefore periodically visit this page to review the then current Privacy Policy to which you are bound. 

#### Updated: September 19, 2006
